Sarah Kimi Rettig

Philadelphia, PA 19129 | sarahkimirettig@gmail.com | https://sarahkimirettig.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I earned my BA and MA in Media Studies that laid the foundation for lifelong learning and gaining mastery over skills in digital media production and design. I have a unicorn skill-set that includes proficiency in coding, timeline editing, graphic design, and user experience using the latest design and development platforms with traditional techniques.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Poster Design using Al and Adobe Illustrator - May 2024

- Designed poster using Illustrator GenAl features to add vector artwork
- Employed ChatGPT for copy to ensure consistent length and uplifting tone
- Utilized ReType, beta Illustrator AI feature, to match font in image

YouTube Video - PamPam and Adobe Lightroom - July - Aug 2024

- Implemented storyboard template to help plan graphics, video and script
- Employed ChatGPT to review script and rewrite sections to be more concise
- Utilized Adobe Premiere to video edit screen recordings, images and voice over

CodeJeo Vue JS web app ~ July - September 2024 (demo available upon request)

- Developed a Rest API using Node JS and Express and postgreSQL
- Developed a front-end using Vue IS and Vuex (now Pinia) store

Hope Bucket React web app ~ September - Nov 2024

- Developed web app using React taking advantage of Hooks and Context
- Designed UI/UX of app with user testing and Figma prototype

WORK EXPERIENCE

Wordpress/Hubspot Design Specialist - Good Circle Marketing

Gallatin, Tennessee, Remote Contract | August - December 2023

- Designed Figma mockups to present design ideas and explore UX user flows
- Designed content heavy Hubspot CMS website with HUBL/CSS modules
- Created Wordpress websites adhering to branding and content outline

WordPress Web & Graphic Designer - Philadelphia Works Inc.

Philadelphia, PA | May 2022 - March 2023

- Created department Sharepoint portal to exchange design assets and files across departments
- Designed lead generating website landing pages tied to data analytics tags to track marketing efforts
- Designed marketing design deliverables in Canva making use of collaboration features
- Managed plugins and content updates for multiple Wordpress sites and trained content authors

Wordpress Web Designer - Dentalnachos.com

Philadelphia, PA | May - August 2021

- Designed wireframes and mockups using Adobe XD for design reviews
- · Redesigned website navigation to focus on findability and driving traffic to key pages
- Customized WordPress plugin for editable and searchable job postings components
- Streamlined job posts creation process on website after conducting internal interviews

Digital Marketing & Web Admin - American Heritage Federal Credit Union

Philadelphia, PA | November 2020 - May 2021

- Designed Sitefinity CMS pages mocking up in Adobe XD before customizing HTML/CSS
- · Conducted ADA compliance audit of website and update content using Site Improve audit results
- Designed email newsletters and landing pages for Hubspot marketing campaigns

Web Developer & Web Designer - Priority Dispatch Corporation

Salt Lake City, UT | December 2016 - June 2020

- Designed wireframes and prototype mockups using Adobe XD to present in meetings
- Front-End coding of multi-role licensing look-up dashboard in Angular and REST API
- Designed and developed LMS training website in PHP and MySQL
- Collaborated with developers and stakeholders on Agile scrum-ban projects

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Design Software: Generative AI • Adobe Creative Suite • Illustrator • Lightroom • Photoshop • Figma • Canva

Content Management: Hubspot Marketing CMS • Sharepoint Portal • Wordpress • Google Sheets • Content Outlines

Web Development: HTML • CSS • Javascript • React JS • Vue JS • Angular • REST API • PHP • Git • Agile • Kanban

EDUCATION

MA in Media Studies, The New School, New York City, NY, 2005

BA in Media Studies, Scripps College, Claremont, CA, 2003

CERTIFICATIONS

- Product Management & Strategy Certificate, University of Pennsylvania, October 2023
- Hubspot Marketing/CMS Certificate, Hubspot Academy, Dec 2021
- Digital Marketing Nanodegree, Udacity.com , March-May 2020
- UX Design Certificate, V School, SLC Utah, February April 2018
- Javascript Front-End Development Certificate, V School, SLC Utah, Aug Nov 2016